Guide to the Herant A. Katchadourian Papers SC0649
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Herant A. Katchadourian papers
1951-2003
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Katchadourian, Herant A.
SC0649
27.5 Linear Feet and 19937.28 megabytes
Access to Collection
Apart from the materials in 2014-075, the materials are open for research use. Researchers must get permission from University Archivist to access materials in 2014-075. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Human reproduction -- Study and teaching.; Sex instruction.; Villages -- Lebanon.; Slides.; Majdal 'Anjar (Lebanon); Hamburg, David A.; Lindemann, Erich; Katchadourian, Herant A.; Boli, John; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Katchadourian, Herant A.; Stanford University. Program in Human Biology; Williams, Judith R.; Romano, John; Williams, Herbert H.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2002-255
  - Anjar, Culture and Psychopathology in an Armenian Village in Lebanon – final draft chap. 1-2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anjar – final draft chap. 3-4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anjar – final draft chap. 5- end (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Life histories / compositions (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chronic patients (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Anjar – misc. notes (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Value orientation [VO] study (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Census (typescript paper) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters received 1974 [Antranig ??] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - VO worksheets, Anjar (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - VO worksheets, non-Anjar (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - VO means, item by item (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - History (printed source), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - VO – unanalyzed responses (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Anjar census code (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Anjar – general file (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - VO – code sheet for village 6 & 7, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anjar field notes (1 of 3), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Anjar field notes (2 of 3), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Anjar field notes (3 of 3), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Spindler, George and Louise, correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Anjar – Holt, Rinehart and Winston correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Anjar – illustrations (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 1 (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 1 (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 1 (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 2 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 3 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 3 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 4 (1 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 4 (2 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 4 (3 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Materials from Lebanon, Binder 4 (4 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Anjar census (printout) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Anjar – draft pp. 1-163 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Anjar – draft pp. 164-end (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chron file 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chron file 1978 Jan.-May (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chron file 1978 June-Aug. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Chron file 1978 Sept.-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chron file 1979 Jan-Mar. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chron file 1979 April-Aug. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chron file 1979 Sept.-Oct. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chron file 1979 Nov.-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chron file 1980 Jan.-Mar. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chron file 1980 April-June (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chron file 1980 July-Oct. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Chron file 1980 Nov.-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Chron file 1981 Jan.-Mar. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Chron file 1981 April-May (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Chron file 1981 June-July (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chron file 1981 Sept.-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Chron file 1982 Jan.-Mar. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Chron file 1982 April-July (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Chron file 1982 Aug.-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Chron file 1983 Jan.-Mar. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Chron file 1983 April-July (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Chron file 1983 Aug.-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Chron file 1984 Jan.-July (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Chron file 1984 Dec. – 1985 Dec. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Chron file 1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Chron file 1987-89 (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Chron file 1987-89 (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Chron file 1990-91 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Chron file 1992-93 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Chron file 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Albany Medical College, 1990-93 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Alumni Association, Travel/Study Program, list of recommended reading, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Alumni Association, Speakers Program, 1983-85 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Association, Portable Stanford, 1985-87 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - American University of Beirut, 1987-93 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Bancroft, John, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Boli, John, 1982-83 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - California Board of Medical Examiners (licenses) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - CV with photo for H. Katchadourian (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1987-94 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Middle School Project, 1988-90 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Duncan, Beth, correspondence (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript reviews, 1971-73 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - U. of Chicago, Center for Middle Easter Studies, conference 1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Shafer, Jack, World Wide Medical News Services, letter & releases, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Haigazian College, 1982-92 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Romano, John, correspondence, 1958-94 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Romano, John, articles and correspondence, 1976-92 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Romano, John, correspondence, 1965-76 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Faculty reports (on his work), 1968-80 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - M.I.T. Visiting Committee, 1978-85 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Vice Provost of Undergraduate Studies, 1983-84 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Recommendation letters for HK, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Congratulations on HK's appointment as Dean, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Faculty appointment 1976 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Masters & Johnson Institute 1979 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Lougee, Carolyn – H & S, 1979-91 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Wessells, Norm – H & S, 1980-83 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Positions refused (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Miller, Bill – Provost's Office, 1975-78 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rosse, James – Provost's office, 1984-92 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lieberman, Gerald – Provost’s Office, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Conference, University of Aberdeen, “Symposium on Psychiatric Epidemiology,” 1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Conference, “Exploring Human Nature,” Massachusetts, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Committees 1967-69 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Report of the Ombudsman's Interim Study Group Relative to the Creation of a Commission on Campus Protest, June 1, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hamburg, David, correspondence, 1960-66 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Hamburg, David, correspondence, 1967-75 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Hamburg, David, correspondence, 1984-94 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hewlett Foundation, 1986-93 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Gifford, Sanford, 1970-73 and n.d. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Glaser, Robert, 1970-87 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston – correspondence re Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, 1972-1981 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Fundamentals – angry mail, 1970-72 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Schizophrenic family – grant application 1963 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Life Cycle seminar, notes (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1992-95 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1990-92 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1988-91 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1983-87 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Personal, miscellaneous (correspondence, press releases), 1959-79 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Photographs 1959-61 and undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Kennedy, Don – President's office, 1978-91 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Hastorf, Al – Provost's Office, 1981-82 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Hastorf, Al – Provost's Office, 1983-84 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Psychiatry Dept. – correspondence, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Racy, John, 1979-80 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - School of Education, Committee on Psychological Studies in Education, memos, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - School of Education, Dean's Office, memos, 1986-87 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Thacher School, 1988-90 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - University of Virginia, 1988-92 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1972-85 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Fundamentals, Chinese translation, correspondence regarding, 1988-91 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, 6th edition, correspondence regarding, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, 5th edition, correspondence regarding, 1987-89 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, 3rd edition, correspondence regarding, 1986-88 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Sabbatical accrual 1990-95 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - University Fellows Program (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Vaillant, George, letter to, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Appointments and resignations, 1961-76 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Lindemann, Erich, 1970-80 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Williams, Herbert & Judith, letters re Anjar, 1961-66 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Typescript: Attaining Adulthood (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Typescript: Part II (sex and love in adolescence; psychological disorders) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Typescript: Part III (families; educational institutions) (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Typescript: Youth and Subcultures (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Typescript: Runaways and School Dropouts (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Institute for Research on Women and Gender, 1990-91 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - WPO talk 1999 – Keeping Love Alive (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Council on Adolescent Development – Promoting Health Sexuality, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Human bio commencement, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Don Kennedy intro, Fellows Dinner, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Guilt, notes for a talk, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Senior Class Day talks, 1971-97 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Issues in Undergraduate Education – misc. talks (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - AAU: Dinner Address, 4/19/1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Senate (SU) presentation, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Freshman Orientation: Address/Parents, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Resident Associates Talk, Oct. 1982 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Talks to Stanford trustees and senate, 197-84 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Engineering Advisory Committee, Feb. 1981 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Orientation talks, 1976-81 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - UGS 112 Human Sexuality – transcripts of lectures (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, correspondence 1983 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, 4th edition, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, 3rd and 4th edition, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, correspondence 1980 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, correspondence 1978-79 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, correspondence 1973-77 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality, correspondence 1968-70 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Friends of Psychiatry, 1971-79 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Freud conference 1980 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Beirut talks, 1950-58 (notes) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Anthropology and Mental Health, conference on, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Spouse Quarter Course (Stanford Alumni Association) 1972 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Ombudsman talk 1973 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Drug Usage in Adolescence, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Experiences of a University Ombudsman (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous items related to talks (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Problems of Adolescence, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Lecture for seminar "Epidemiological Studies in Community Psychiatry" – correspondence 1968 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Psychology and Near East Studies conference – notes for talk, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Transcultural Aspects of Sexuality, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Assorted talks, 1954-69 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Fresno talk, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Freshman seminar 1968 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - History of Psychiatry (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Existential Psychoanalysis (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Social Class and Mental Illness, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Lectures at American University Hospital, 1962-66 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Social Psychiatry, recorder's summary, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - LSD (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Adolescence: Clinical and Historical Considerations 1968 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Clinical Aspects of Aggression, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Social Psychiatry Seminar, 1968-71 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Physiology of Sexual Response (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Social Psych Seminar 1968 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Pastoral Conference, Berkeley, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Advising/Counseling/Psychotherapy treatment of students at Stanford, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Non-sex uses of sex (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Sex and the Aged, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Human Bio 4B: Marital Conflict and Divorce 1986-90 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Lectures, talk, misc. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - San Diego Academy of General Practice, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Human Sexuality Sense and Nonsense (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - University of Rochester, 25th Anniversary, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - American College of Physicians 1990 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - President's Scholars Talk, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Middle Grades Human Biology Curriculum Project [overhead projection pages] (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Cohort Study talks, 1993 and undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous talks 1976-95 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Arab talk, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Possible future talks (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Address: Principles of Private Schools [?] 1983-85 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Oakland Prep School [talk on sexuality and risk taking at Oakland and others] 1988 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous 1987 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Carnegie Conference, 1989, "A Common Core of Learning" (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Stanford Alumni Association talks, 1972-81 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Non-sexual uses of sex (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Alumni Association, 1972-78 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Alumni/Spouse Quarter Course (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Alumni – Life Cycle talk [plus others], 1974-80 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Nina Zelanger, interview with HK, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Hum Bio graduation address, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - The Teaching Company, correspondence and outline of course (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Life Science Curriculum for the Middle Grades, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Black, John, profile on HK, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Assorted talks (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Fundamentals: permissions, 1st edition (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Fundamentals: Adoption list (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Fundamentals: Royalty statements (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Fundamentals: correspondence, 1971-72 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Fundamentals: Eitner, Lorenz, 1969-80 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Fundamentals: Lunde, Donald, 1969, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Fundamentals: International, 1973-82 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Fundamentals: Purdy, Strother, 1969-81 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Fundamentals: Trade (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Fundamentals: Contracts (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Fundamentals: Mailing list (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Fundamentals: Publicity (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Fundamentals: Reviews (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Starting Points Conference, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Albany Medical College course, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The Twain Shall Never Meet – notes for talk on Mark Twain, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Sex Role Stereotyping 1972 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Future Shock, Cross Cultural Observations 1971 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Conference on Anthropology and Mental Health, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Communities in Crisis (After Musa Dagh: Group coping and psychiatric illness in a resettled refugee community), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Contraception – Psychological Implications, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Middle Schools Adv. Board presentation, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous talks (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Episcopal Clergy Conference 1977 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Univ. of Rochester, dept. of psychiatry: 20th anniversary talk, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Good Thinking, Inc.: Sexuality lecture, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Social Psych. Seminar (Psychiatric Epidemiology) 1970-71 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Introduction lecture for Human Sexuality course, 1968-72 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Anatomy, 1969-73 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Social Psychiatry – bibliographic references (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Psychiatry lectures, AUB, 1955-68 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Pride and Prejudice (#112) (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Varieties of Sexual Experience (#112) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Psychosexual Development of Man (#112) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Functional Gonadal Relationships (#112) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Deviation of the Sexual Impulse (#112) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Sexual Malfunction (#112) (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - A Child is Born (#112) (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Morality (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Armenian Identity 1979 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - HK's student notes, general education 1951-52, part 1 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - HK's student notes, general education 1951-52, part 2 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - HK's student notes, general education 1951-52, part 3 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - HK's student notes, general education 1951-52, part 4 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - HK's student notes, medical studies, ca.1955, part 1 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - HK's student notes, medical studies, ca.1955, part 2 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - HK's student notes, medical studies, ca.1955, part 3 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - HK's student notes, medical studies, ca.1955, part 4 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - SUMC course, Sexual Dysfunction, 1995-98 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Life Cycle Seminar (Hum Bio 153), Spring 1973) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Human Biology core, guest speakers 1993 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Human Biology core, 4B, 1992-93 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Human Biology Core 4B, Spring 1992 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Human Biology Core 4B, Spring 1991 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Human Biology Core 4B, Spring 1990 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Human Biology Core 4B, Spring 1989 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Human Biology Core 4B, Spring 1987 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Human Biology Core 4B, Spring 1986 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Human Biology Core syllabi 1984-1992 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Human Biology Core 4B, proposal for core revision, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Great Works, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Great Works, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Adulthood course Spring 1987 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Adulthood, spring 1986/87 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Adulthood 1987-88 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Adulthood, winter 1988/89 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Adulthood 1989 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Adulthood, winter 1989/90 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Assessment of Undergraduate Education at Stanford, Class of 1981 – blank survey form [cohort study], 1990 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Undergraduate Special 112 [Human Sexuality], course proposal 1967 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Undergraduate Special 112, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Undergraduate Special 112, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Undergraduate Special 112, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Undergraduate Special 193 [Human Sexuality], 1971 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - HB 10 Human Sex, Winter 1971/72 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - HB 10 Human Sex, Winter 1972/73 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - HB 10, syllabus and notes, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - HB 10 Human Sex, Spring 1973/74 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - HB 10 Human Sex, Winter 1975/76 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - HB 10 Human Sex, Winter 1976/77 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - HB 10 Human Sex, Winter 1977/78 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - HB 10 Human Sex, Winter 1978/79 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - HB 10 Human Sex, 1979/80 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1980-81 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1982-83 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1983-84 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1985-86 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1986-87 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1987-88 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1988-89 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1989-90 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1990-91 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1991-81 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1992-93 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1993-94 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1993-94 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, 1994-95 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 1995-96, Syllabus, grade distribution (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 1995-96, Midterm exam (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 1995-96, Final exam (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Winter 1996-97, Syllabus, grade distribution (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Winter 1996-97, Midterm exam (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Winter 1996-97, Final exam (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Winter 1997-98, Syllabus and grade distribution (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Winter 1997-98, Midterm exam (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Winter 1997-98, Final exam (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Reserve sheets for lecture tapes (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Winter 1997/98-1998/99, Syllabus (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Hum Bio 10 1998-99, lecture slides [disk and paper copies] (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Hum Bio 10 1998-99, midterm exam (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Hum Bio 10 1998-99, final exam (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Hum Bio 10 Spring 1999-2000 (includes 3 computer disks) (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 2001 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 2002 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 2002, lecture slides (paper copy) (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 2002, lecture slides (paper copy) (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 2002, lecture slides (paper copy) (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 2002, lecture slides (paper copy) (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 2002, lecture slides (paper copy) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Human Biology 10 Human Sexuality, Spring 2002, lecture slides (paper copy) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Human Sexuality Class, 1968-69, student evaluations (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Human Sexuality Class, 1972-73, evaluations by female students (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Human Sexuality Class, 1972-73, evaluations by female (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Human Sexuality Class, 1972-73, evaluations by male students (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Human Sexuality Class, 1972-73, evaluations by male students (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous evaluations (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Philp, Julie, "Guilt and Shame: Prevalence and Patterns in Japanese and American Children's Books" (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Herant Katchadourian, M.D. Press Information [mostly articles] (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Press kit, extra copy (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Reviews of HK's books (Xeroxed clippings) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - HK's career in clippings (Xeroxed) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - C.V. and short biography (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Careerism and Intellectualism – reviews and correspondence, 1985-86 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Careerism and Intellectualism – reviews with some correspondence, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Fundamentals of Human Sexuality and 50: Midlife in Perspective – reviews (Box 23, Folder 8)